<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>THE TRANSCREATORS | MORE THAN TRANSLATORS | LOCALIZATION COPYWRITERS | GERMAN &gt; ENGLISH | FRENCH &gt; ENGLISH</title>
    <link href="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators" />
    <updated>2022-07-18T12:42:18+02:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Mark</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Zeigen Sie, dass Sie seriös sind?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Mark</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/zeigen-sie-dass-sie-serioes-sind.html"/>
        <id>https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/zeigen-sie-dass-sie-serioes-sind.html</id>

        <updated>2022-07-14T18:32:23+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/media/posts/10/serioes_16-9.png" alt="" />
                    Wenn die englische Texte, die Sie veröffentlichen, klar und einfach sind, treten Menschen von überall auf der Welt gerne mit Ihnen ins Geschäft. Aber wie genau lassen sich Texte im Englischen erstellen, die nicht nur 100%-ig verständlich sondern auch wirklich&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/media/posts/10/serioes_16-9.png" alt="" />
                <p>Wenn die englische Texte, die Sie veröffentlichen, klar und einfach sind, treten Menschen von überall auf der Welt gerne mit Ihnen ins Geschäft.<br><br>Aber wie genau lassen sich Texte im Englischen erstellen, die nicht nur 100%-ig verständlich sondern auch wirklich überzeugend sind? Reicht eine maschinielle Übersetzung? Konnen wir es selber machen (schließlich kann jeder hier Englisch)? Oder wollen wir eine preiswerte Übersetzungsagentur suchen?</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Almost, but not quite, entirely unlike native English</title>
        <author>
            <name>Mark</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/almost-but-not-quite-entirely-unlike-native-english.html"/>
        <id>https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/almost-but-not-quite-entirely-unlike-native-english.html</id>

        <updated>2022-07-14T18:13:30+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/media/posts/9/entirely_unlike_16-9-2.png" alt="" />
                    Assuming pretty much everyone who graduated high school in the last 20 to 30 years can speak and often even write at least a little English would be a fairly good presumption. In our globalized world, English has become a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/media/posts/9/entirely_unlike_16-9-2.png" alt="" />
                <p>Assuming pretty much everyone who graduated high school in the last 20 to 30 years can speak and often even write at least a little English would be a fairly good presumption. In our globalized world, English has become a tool for communication, especially in business, science and education. Although English might not be the most spoken first language (L1), it is by far the most widely spoken second language (L2) with more than a billion speakers globally. Add these to the approximately 370 million L1 English speakers equates to more than 16% of the global population conversing in English on a regular basis.</p>
<p>Undoubtably such a large number of people speaking English on a regular basis leads to some L2 speakers being capable of producing translations that some L1 speakers would assume were written by a native speaker. However, on closer inspection most L1 speakers would conclude that something is not quite right, or even stilted with such translations.</p>
<p>This ‘something-is-not-quite-right’ feeling often pertains to many areas such as the lexis used, sentence and grammatical structure, not to mention a lack of localization and in some cases a misinterpretation of the source text, which can mislead the reader – your potential new client. If I had a Dollar for every translation I’ve come across where I’ve had this ‘something-is-not-quite-right’ feeling I’d be living a very comfortable life indeed.</p>
<p><strong>Why does this ‘something-is-not-quite-right’ feeling happen so often?</strong></p>
<p>It’s pretty simple. Most businesses have someone amongst their ranks who has a good command of the English language and can write to a reasonably high standard. This person is often then given the task of translating documents, brochures, and even the company website. Whilst this would not necessarily be an issue for standard email communication with clients, it can become a serious issue when it comes to print and online media leading to misunderstandings, a lack of localization and ultimately giving your media an unprofessional feel to it.</p>
<p><strong>What can I do to make sure my copy does not have that ‘something-is-not-quite-right’ feeling? </strong></p>
<p>In a nutshell, use a transcreator. A well transcreated piece of copy will eliminate that ‘something-is-not-quite-right’ feeling and evoke the emotions necessary for a reader to buy in to your message. A transcreator guarantees your copy will be clear of misinterpretation and misunderstanding and is localized to your target market.</p>
<p>What are you waiting for? Get peace of mind and get rid of that ‘something-is-not-quite-right’ feeling today!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Isn&#x27;t machine translation good enough these days?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Mark</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/machine-translation.html"/>
        <id>https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/machine-translation.html</id>

        <updated>2022-07-18T12:42:18+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/media/posts/6/google_translate_example_de-en_16-9.png" alt="" />
                    Well, it depends how "over, thick and full" you want it (see above). That's a nice example of how a machine translation can be just silly. It can be useful sometimes though. It can help with email exchanges, or if&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/media/posts/6/google_translate_example_de-en_16-9.png" alt="" />
                <p>Well, it depends how "over, thick and full" you want it (see above). That's a nice example of how a machine translation can be just silly. It <em>can </em>be useful sometimes though. It can help with email exchanges, or if you need to quickly translate something you're reading into your language. These are situations where everybody knows and accepts that they're going to have to work a little harder to understand what is meant, and that some things won't be immediately clear, and that some things might be completely unclear.</p>
<p>Using machine translation can be fun, when everybody's on board with it and willing to make an effort.</p>
<p>Have you noticed, however, how it is suddenly not at all fun when you are reading a piece of website text, for example, and you start to suspect that machine translation has been used for it?</p>
<p>In the case of English, certainly, machine translation is not good enough. Yes, I am boldy making that bold statement. English is the de-facto lingua franca of the world and there is no way around that. A company needs to show that it knows how to do things properly, not necessarily for every last piece of written material, but for the main things.</p>
<p>If I see a bad translation into English, I always thing the same thing:</p>
<ul>
<li>Are they too lazy to have a proper translation done? What else are they too lazy to do properly?</li>
<li>Do they not think that clear communication is important? What else do they not think is important?</li>
<li>Do they not realize how bad the English is here? What else do the not realize is bad?</li>
<li>Can they not be bothered to get the English checked by a qualified expert (who is also a native speaker of English)? What else can they not be bothered to get checked by a qualified expert?</li>
</ul>
<p>What do you think?</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Transcreation vs. translation</title>
        <author>
            <name>Mark</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/what-is-transcreation.html"/>
        <id>https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/what-is-transcreation.html</id>

        <updated>2022-07-18T11:34:19+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/media/posts/5/rise_above_the_fog6_16-9.png" alt="" />
                    Sometimes with a conventional translation, the message can get quite confused. So can the reader. What's different about transrcreation? What exactly is it? Why is a transcreated message clearer, and more powerful? Transcreation uses imagery that resonates in the minds&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/media/posts/5/rise_above_the_fog6_16-9.png" alt="" />
                <p>Sometimes with a conventional translation, the message can get quite confused. So can the reader. What's different about transrcreation? What exactly is it? Why is a transcreated message clearer, and more powerful?</p>
<p>Transcreation uses imagery that resonates in the minds of the target readership. Localization copyrighting is another, possibly more self-explanatory term for transcreation. Call it what you like, it involves a whole extra level of creative input. It is the process of <em>rewriting </em>a piece of text in another language. Translation on the other hand tends to stay fairly close to the words of the source text.</p>
<p>A well transcreated piece of copy might on the face of it seem to have nothing at all to do with the source. But it will have the same effect on the readership. And evoke the emotions (culturally adjusted) necessary for them to buy in to your message.</p>
<p>Can anybody with good knowledge of both languages do it? No. You need much more than that. Even truly bilingual people (that is people who have been immersed in two languages from birth and effectively have two mother tongues) would struggle to sufficiently distance themselves from the source. Even regular straightforward translation is astonishingly difficult for those who have not spent a long time practicing.</p>
<p><strong>Transcreators need all of these things</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">To be native speakers of the target language</span></li>
<li>A lot of experience doing real commercial translations</li>
<li>A genuine fascination for language and the art of transcreation</li>
<li>The motivation and determination to go the extra mile</li>
<li>Creativity and a well-developed ability to think laterally</li>
<li>The confidence to be able to reject their own ideas</li>
<li>The confidence to be able to  reject the client's own ideas</li>
<li>To NOT be under unrealistic time or economic pressure</li>
</ul>
<p>Notice that confidence plays a big part. If anything, it is a bit downplayed in that list. It is, however, absolutely essential. But it must be well-founded. It must be based on experience and knowledge and not on exuberant overconfidence, and certainly NOTHING TO DO with any kind of fake-it-till-you-make-it nonsense.</p>
<p>I have the confidence and the knowledge, it has taken many, many years and thousands of hours of brain-racking and almost obsessive application to bulid up (all under control, don't worry I'm not a weirdo).</p>
<p>Get in touch and give me any kind of transcreation test you like.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Would you translate this as &quot;In a train to Tirol&quot;?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Mark</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/in-einem-zug.html"/>
        <id>https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/in-einem-zug.html</id>

        <updated>2022-07-18T12:21:44+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/media/posts/1/in_einem_zug_16-9.png" alt="" />
                    I have seen this sign many times and have always admired the excellent wordplay. As far as I know there is no English version of this ad, and I don't think there needs to be one. I'm pretty sure it&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/media/posts/1/in_einem_zug_16-9.png" alt="" />
                <p>I have seen this sign many times and have always admired the excellent wordplay. As far as I know there is no English version of this ad, and I don't think there needs to be one. I'm pretty sure it is aimed primarily at German visitors to Tirol in Austria.</p>
<p>I'm going to try to transcreate it into English anyway, just for fun, and as a quick example of the transcreation process.</p>
<p>Right. What's the message?</p>
<ul>
<li>We encourage you to go to Tirol by train instead of by car</li>
<li>You can go directly, even from Germany</li>
</ul>
<p>The word-for-word translation "In a train to Tirol" is, of course, not a proper translation. It doesn't even transfer one of the two elements of the message contained in the German wordplay. In fact, in English it comes across as no more than a fairly pointless statement. It just hangs in the air. A normal translator might still be tempted to use it though. You can understand why if you remember that regular, jobbing translators are mostly paid per word, and as little per word as the customer or agency can get away with. On top of that, they are usually not provided with the context needed to do a proper job.</p>
<p>It is clear that what makes the message stick in your head is the excellent wordplay. It reverberates in the mind. Can we find an equivalent in English? Well, although you could translate the German expression "in einem Zug" into English as "in one fell swoop" or "(all) in one go", neither is usable in this context.</p>
<p>Oh dear.</p>
<p>If we don't have a wordplay, what can we do instead that would be similar in its effect on the reader?</p>
<p>We could use a different literary device. Alliteration, for example, rather than wordplay. I have one idea. I don't like it as much as the source, but it would work, and, importantly, it is usable for the intended purpose, and it contains both elements of the message:</p>
<p><strong>"Take the train straight to Tirol"</strong></p>
<p><strong>This would work.</strong></p>
<p>Maybe if a driver saw that a few times on a stretch of road (there are several of these ads on billboards placed along certain sections of trunk road), it might start off a brainworm (a brainworm is my own term for something that gets stuck in your head a bit like an earworm, except that it's a phrase rather than a piece of music). Hmm... I'm starting to like it more. If you say it a few times to yourself, the rhythm starts to sound like a train clacking along the track.</p>
<p>It's good to like your own ideas... but not too much!</p>
<p>So I asked Warren (the other author on this blog) if he had any ideas. Without thinking about it too much, he suggested:</p>
<p><strong>"Non-stop all the way to Tirol"</strong></p>
<p><strong>This would not work.</strong></p>
<p>Yes, it seems very good at first glance. Actually, both of our initial reactions were that this was better than my idea. Then we quickly realized that it was unusable. Whether or not it is really non-stop depends on where you start your journey. One of the cleverest things about the German original is that it uses the established expression "in einem Zug" to <em>imply </em>that it will be non-stop without making any impossible claims. You understand that the trip will be quick, but you will accept that you might need to change trains at some point in the journey. And for German visitors, the message that trains run directly from Germany into Austria is still clear. Wonderful stuff!</p>
<p>That's a great illustration of how we work (whether together or separately). We will throw any and all ideas into the air, but not fall in love with any of them. Then we think things all the way through to the end. And we never forget the power of a word. The power to get a message across clearly. Or the power to mislead and confuse.</p>
<p>If you are from the company Tirol Info, then I would like to say that you have my sincere admiration for a great strapline in German. And although my English version is probably not quite as good, I still claim copyright to it. So if you want to use it, please get in touch first.</p>
<p>And whoever you are, if you can think of something better, I'd love to know what it is. Just out of interest.</p>
<p>So, there's a quick and real example of what transcreation is all about. And it <em>is</em> rather fun, isn't it?</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Nobody benefits from a rush job</title>
        <author>
            <name>Mark</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/nobody-benefits-from-a-rush-job.html"/>
        <id>https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/nobody-benefits-from-a-rush-job.html</id>

        <updated>2022-07-14T18:18:41+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/media/posts/8/pexels-helena-lopes-3867001.png" alt="" />
                    Translators the world over loath them for good reasons – the rush jobs. To set the scene, it’s Thursday evening, or even worse, Friday morning when a client sends out a text that needs to be translated by Monday. For&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/media/posts/8/pexels-helena-lopes-3867001.png" alt="" />
                <p>Translators the world over loath them for good reasons – the rush jobs. To set the scene, it’s Thursday evening, or even worse, Friday morning when a client sends out a text that needs to be translated by Monday. For fear of losing revenue, or even worse a client, the translator agrees to deliver the completed translation in the requested time frame. In some cases, this won’t be such a big deal as it is a small and therefore manageable job. However, all too often it’s a bigger job that warrants more time than the client realizes to deliver quality work resulting in, you guessed it, a rush job. The translator spends the weekend sweating over large volumes of text, sometimes technical in nature, with the looming deadline in mind and ends up delivering substandard or even inaccurate results simply to get the job done on time. Neither client nor translator benefit from a rush job.</p>
<p><strong>Why do rush jobs happen?</strong></p>
<p>Rush jobs usually happen when a client is busy working on several projects at a time and realizes they are behind schedule. Often, they will then complete a text as quickly as possible and send it off to the translator with a tight, and often unrealistic, deadline in order to tick off the task from their long to-do list. This often happens towards the end of the working week and in some cases the translator is left to decipher a source text that is not particularly well written or structured leading to inaccuracies as the client is not available at the weekend. </p>
<p><strong>What can be done to avoid rush jobs and improve quality?</strong></p>
<p>Some simple steps can be taken to avoid rush jobs and improve quality. Firstly, a client needs to understand the value and importance of quality localized translations, especially when it comes to print or online media. Secondly, clients need to factor in time for translations when planning new projects. This point is often completely overlooked or underestimated. Finally, clients need to involve translators more in the planning process so realistic lead times for quality translations can be agreed upon.</p>
<p>Contact us today to learn more about how we can help you to improve the quality of your translated texts and get ahead of your competitors!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Customers don&#x27;t want to work hard trying to figure out what you mean</title>
        <author>
            <name>Mark</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/customers-want-clarity.html"/>
        <id>https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/customers-want-clarity.html</id>

        <updated>2022-07-04T13:11:31+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/media/posts/2/alpacas_1920x1080-2.png" alt="" />
                    Your marketing copy must be crystal clear or it risks being ignored. There are a lot of voices out there and if you are trying to sell something you need to grab and hold attention. But you already know that.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://the-transcreators.github.io/more-than-translators/media/posts/2/alpacas_1920x1080-2.png" alt="" />
                <p>Your marketing copy must be crystal clear or it risks being ignored. There are a lot of voices out there and if you are trying to sell something you need to grab and hold attention. But you already know that. Of course you do. And I bet you take a lot of care to get the source text right in the original language. That's easy for you to do if the source language is your language. But what about the English translation? Are you sure that you are as sensitive to what might be wrong with that? Be very careful here, because sometimes the translation can look good to you because you recognize each element from the source. BUT, those elements may be completely meaningless in the English-speaking world. In fact, sometimes the translation that looks best to a native speaker of the source language is the hardest to understand for a native speaker of the target language. How can you know what is right?</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
